JORGE CASTAÑO

Tech Lead - Front End Engineer

INFO

PHONE

(+34) 619 54 03 55

EMAIL

hola@jorge-castano.com

WEB

http://jorge-castano.com/

LINKEDIN

linkedin.com/in/jorge-castaño

TOP SKILLS

JavaScript

HTML5 & CSS3

React

Angular

Public Speaking

Humor

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English

German

EDUCATION

MSc. Telecom Engineer

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid (UPM)

RWTH Aachen

ABOUT ME

I have worked in many different **JavaScript** projects such as fintech, banks, health care, automobile & videogames, for start-ups and top tech companies.

I am a **ReactJS** enthusiast, but I also have experience with **Angular (5+), VueJS, React Native and Backbone**.

EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead - Front End Developer

Daimler

Oct 2019 – Present

Created many projects from draft to deployment for Mercedes-Benz and Daimler AG. Front End Architecture & Development with **ReactJS**. Mentorship for junior developers, Code reviews & pair programming.

Front End Developer

Minsait (indra)

Jan 2017 - Sep 2019

Front End Architecture & Development for BBVA, Bankinter, Santalucía, and Pull & Bear (Inditex) with **Angular, Backbone & Vue**. Code reviews and development design. Unit Testing with TapeJS & E2E Testing with Selenium.

Mobile & Front End Developer

Aslam, New IT

Mar 2015 - Dec 2016

Mobile & Front end development for PSA Peugeot Citroën and Capgemini. **Hybrid mobile apps:** Cordova, Backbone & Marionette. **Front End:** HTML, CSS & JavaScript. Ajax + REST Services.

FullStack Developer

Krama, e-soft

Apr 2014 – Mar 2015

Front and Back End development for Canal +, Banco popular and AtlCapital. **FullStack Technologies:** JavaScript + jQuery, HTML, CSS, Java, Struts, JSP. **Hybrid mobile apps:** Cordova, IBM MobileFirst, Android.